insectlore.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

Thank you for accessing the Insectlore.com Website (“Site”) operated by Insect Lore Products Inc.. We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to information submitted on the Site and to information submitted to Insect Lore Products via Facebook or Twitter. To learn more, please read this Privacy Policy. 

 **1\. Information Collection**

 **Information You Give to Us** : We collect personal information that is provided by Site users. "Personal Information" includes, but is not limited to, your name, address, telephone number, credit or debit card information, e-mail address, date of birth, gender and IP address. Personal Information is collected when you establish an account with us, place an order on the Site, participate in a contest, sweepstakes or on-line survey, or when you communicate with any of our departments such as customer service, sales or support services through the Site, telephone, mail or fax. In some instances, we may obtain other people’s names and email addresses that you may choose to provide as part of our "email a friend" feature. We may also maintain a record of your product purchases. 

Whether or not you provide such information is completely your own choice. However, if you choose not to provide the information we request, you may be unable to purchase products, or access certain services, offers and content on our Site. In addition, we may need to contact you via phone, email or mail to address questions or issues specific to your order, entry, etc., even if you have opted to not receive marketing communications from us. 

In general, you can visit many of our web pages without telling us who you are or revealing any contact information about yourself. We may track the Internet domain address from which people visit us and analyze this data for preferences, trends, and Site usage statistics, but individual users will remain anonymous, unless you voluntarily tell us who you are. 

 **Cookies[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** When you visit our web sites, we send one or more "cookies" to your computer or other device. We may also use cookies in emails that you receive from us. A "cookie" is a small data file that is placed on the hard drive of your computer when you visit a web site. A "persistent cookie" stores information on the hard drive so that when you end your session and return to the same web site at a later date the cookie information is still available. We do not set any personally identifiable information in cookies, nor do we employ any data capture mechanisms on our Site other than cookies. Generally, we use cookies to improve the quality of our service when you visit our web site and other web sites of interest to you. We also use cookies to remind us of who you are, tailor our products, services and advertising to suit the personal interests of you and others, estimate our audience size, assist our online merchants to track visits to and sales at our web sites and to process your order, track your status in our promotions, contests and sweepstakes, and/or analyze your visiting patterns. 

 **Log Files[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** As is true of most web sites, the Site server automatically recognizes the Internet URL from which you access the Site. We may also log your Internet protocol (“IP”) address, Internet service provider, and date/time stamp for system administration, order verification, internal marketing, and system troubleshooting purposes. An IP address may indicate the location of your computer on the Internet, but does not reveal any personal information. The Site may also gather anonymous “traffic data” that does not personally identify you, but that may be used for marketing purposes or to improve the services we offer. 

 **2\. Internal Use of your Information**

 **Internal Use[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** We use your personal information to process your order and provide you with customer service. We may internally use your personal information to improve the Site’s content and layout, to improve outreach and for our own marketing efforts (including marketing our services and products to you), and to determine general marketplace information about visitors to the Site. In order to facilitate such use and the other use described in this Section 3, we may share your information with affiliates under Insect Lore’s control. When we collect personal information about you, we may process the information outside the country where you are located, including, but not limited to, the United States of America. The countries in which we process information may not have the same data protection policies as the country in which you are located. 

 **Communications with You[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** We will use your personal information to communicate with you about the Site and your orders and deliveries. Also, we may send you a confirmation email when you register with us. We may send you a service-related announcement on the rare occasions when it is necessary (for example, if we must temporarily suspend our service for maintenance.) Also, you may submit your email address for reasons such as to register for a contest or sweepstakes; to request us to notify you of new brands or new product; to sign up for email newsletters and special offers; or to sign up for the Insect Lore Newsletter. If you submit your email address, we use it to deliver the requested information to you. We always permit you to unsubscribe or opt out of future emails (see the opt-out section, below, for more details). Because we have to communicate with you about orders that you choose to place, you cannot opt out of receiving emails related to your orders. 

 **3\. Information We Share with Others**

We only share personal information in the following circumstances:

 **Service Providers[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** As do most catalog and Internet retailers, we contract with other companies to provide certain services, including shipping, name and address verification, email distribution, market research, promotions management and payment processing. We provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services and work closely with them to ensure that your privacy is respected and protected. For example, in order to deliver products to you, we must share some information. We partner with third parties (such as the U.S. Postal Service, United Parcel Service, and Federal Express) to ship products, to ensure delivery, and so that we can obtain feedback, improve the quality of our service, and measure and improve the quality of the service of the third party. In the example of shippers, we provide them some personally identifiable information such as your name, shipping address, email, and phone number. 

 **Select Partners[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** From time to time we might establish a business relationship with other persons or entities whom we believe trustworthy and whom we have asked to confirm that their privacy policies are consistent with ours. These are known as our Select Partners. In such cases we might rent, exchange, share and/or cross-reference information, including contact information about you that will enable such persons or entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you. 

 **Law Enforcement[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** In certain instances we may disclose your contact information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities that may be causing injury to you, to others or to our Site or brands. We may also disclose your contact information when we have a good faith belief the law or legal process requires it. 

 **Consent[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** We may share your personal information when you consent to the sharing of information or direct us to share the information. 

 **Merger or Sale[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** In order to accommodate changes in our business, we may sell or buy portions of our company or other companies or assets, including the information collected through the Site. If Insect Lore Products or substantially all of its assets are acquired by another company, customer information will be one of the assets transferred to the acquiring party. 

 **4\. Things That Are Not Covered. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the following:**

 **Public Posting[:](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** Any information that you choose to provide in a public are of the Site will not be protected by this Privacy Policy because you have made an active choice to make the information public. 

 **Aggregated Non-Personal Information and Other Information without Personal Identification[.](http://www.insectlore.com/shop.axd/PrivacyPolicyInfo)** Although we will not share your personal information with third parties except as permitted above, we may share aggregate anonymous information with third parties. This information does not personally identify individuals, but instead provides a helpful understanding of the groups of people who prefer certain types of information and services. 

 **5\. Opt-Out**

We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. If you prefer not to receive direct marketing from us or from our Select Partners, or if you would like to opt out of our exchange of your information with other marketers, please let us know. You can make these requests at the customer information section of the Site http://www.insectlore.com, or by telephoning, or emailing your request to Insect Lore’s Customer Loyalty Team 1-800-213-6124 or privacy@insectlore.com. Please be sure to include your full name, email address, mailing address, and specifically what information you do not want to receive. 

Please do not email your credit-card number or other sensitive information. 

Please note that any requests to remove or update your contact information may take up to ten days for your email request and 6-8 weeks to process your postal mail request. 

 **6\. Children and Privacy  **

Our Site is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn or have reason to suspect that a Site user is under the age of 13, we will promptly delete any personal information in that user’s account. 

 **7\. Policy Changes**

From time to time, we may use customer information for unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this Privacy Policy. If our information practices change, we will post these changes on our Site and such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically to ensure that you continue to agree with it. 

 **8\. Security**

We employ 128-bit encryption technology in all areas of the Site which require you to provide your personal or account information, including those areas related to online ordering, order status, catalog request and contest forms. The Site utilizes industry-standard firewalls and Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to allow for the encryption of potentially sensitive Personal Information, such as your name, address and credit card number. 

You should recognize, however, that no computer system is fully secure and that there are inherent risks associated with Internet transactions. To make sure you have the latest security features on your browser, you may want to download the most recent version of your favorite browser, which should have full SSL support. 

 **9\. Questions or Comments**

We always welcome your questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, please contact us by clicking [here](http://staging.insectlore.com/contacts/ "Contact Us").
